CARISSA FARRY HILMI AZ ZAHRA

linkedin: carissafarry \diamond carissafarry@gmail.com \diamond carissafarry.vercel.app

Summary -

I am a passionate Programmer who love applying best practice for each of my project. I am an expert in Back End Development, Virtual Machines, Node.js, NGINX as a reverse proxy, Docker deployment, MySQL database, and proficient in GitHub Actions for CI/CD. As a Backend Engineer, I am also experienced with Appwrite for cloud Backend as a Service, connecting it to front-end projects using TypeScript. Through my last experience in Apple Developer Academy, I have further enriched my skill set by actively engaged in developing within the Apple Environment.

Experience -

Apple Developer Academy @ UC | iOS Developer, Product & Project Manager Internship Mar 2023 - Dec 2023

- Trained **over 100 videos** to achieve a **98% accuracy rate** in **movement classification** for a body motion detection using **Core ML**.
- Successfully retrieve daily user health data, including standing minutes and step counts, using HealthKit.
- Successfully extract gyroscope data from the Apple Watch using **Core Motion** and established **seamless data transfer** between iOS using **Watch Connectivity** and **HealthKit Session**.
- Achieved 80% accuracy in applying gyroscope data as physics effects to a 2D object within SceneKit.
- Accomplished the integration of automatic object placement and interactive gestures using ARKit.
- Conducted user feedback, including User Testing and Usability Testing with 3 teachers, parents, 10 children, and 2 schools, resulting in an 80% improvement in engagement rates.

PT. Terobosan Anak Bangsa | Backend Engineer Part Time

Sept 2022 - Present

- Expanded user base up to **1800 members** by developing the backend of the web platform using **Vue.js**, **TypeScript**, **Pinia**, **and Appwrite**.
- Successfully developed a **live transcription feature** using the **Web Speech API** and expanded it to include **file-based transcription** using **Deepgram**, supporting multiple languages.
- Successfully developed a transcription room enabling multiple users to transcribe simultaneously by utilizing Socket.IO.
- Building a Zoom client marketplace app by utilizing WebRTC and Socket.IO enabling live synchronous system between platforms.

UPN Veterans East Java | Backend Developer Freelance

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- Successfully implemented dynamic shuffled questions in a computer-based exam application using the Laravel framework.
- Established a robust bidirectional flow of requests between the client and the server for **150 participants** by implementing an **asynchronous system** on the **VPS**.
- Executed production in a Docker environment using CI/CD.

Diskominfo Jawa Timur | Web Developer Internship

Jul 2021 - Sept 2021

• Implemented the **Spatie Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)** system in a Host Management Web Application using **Laravel** and a **MySQL database**.

Skills -

Swift • Vue.js • Next.js • React.js • TypeScript • Node.js • Git • Appwrite • NGINX • Docker • MySQL • TailwindCSS • C/C++ • Python • Java • Oracle

Projects -

Moco Kids | Developer, Product & Project Manager Moco Kids

October 2023 - Present

• Moco is an iOS application that will assist your child in reading comprehension through interactive activities such as flashcards, mazes, and an interactive AR world.

Bowlmo Bowlmo Jul 2023 - Aug 2023

• Bowlmo is a Bowling Game that allows users to throw a ball using their Apple Watch, calculating rotation and speed in the throwing force.

Petto Life | Developer Petto Life

Jun 2023 - Jul 2023

Petto Life is an iOS App that provides users with relaxation activity reminder through game which is by taking care
of a pet and compete through leaderboard.

RedCal RedCal May 2023

RedCal is simple app that help track menstrual cycle and predict the next period.

More about my work, check out my Github.

Education -

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya Diploma 3 Degree

Major in Informatics Engineering.

Diploma Thesis: Internal Quality Audit Information System

Thesis Tech Stack: MVC PHP Native, Oracle

GPA: 3.75 / 4.0

Achievement -

Toyota Astra Financial Incubation | Awardee Online Incubation

Nov 2021 - Des 2021

- Being 1 of 20 people selected from 160 candidates, I received training on project management, data analysis, digital technology trends, IT infrastructure, and cyber security.
- Collaborated with 4 other members to create a technology-related business plan at TAF within a week, involving market analysis, product research, and competitor analysis.
- Earned the **Best Group Collaboration Award** by actively participating in daily challenges.

Coursework -

Foundations of Project Management | Google, Coursera

Aug 2023

• Project Management • Change Management • Strategic Thinking • Career Development • Organizational Culture

Data Science Course | PKS Digital School

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

• Basic Python • Data Scientist Library and Package • Basic SQL • NLP • Final score of 93 points out of 100

Activity Experience

Secretary I, Forum Mahasiswa Tulungagung se-Surabaya

Aug 2021 - Jul 2022

Perform the functions of control, coordination, development and improvement of administrative and financial management systems as well as communication in building internal and external relations of the organization.

Chairman, UKM Teknologi dan Kesehatan PENS

Mar 2021 - Feb 2022

Adhering to the general policy of the administrator, responsible for all organizational activities, presided over every comprehensive board meeting, responsible both inside and outside the organization, and carry out management reshuffles if necessary.

External Relations Department Staff, Forum Mahasiswa Tulungagung se-Surabaya

Oct 2020 - Jul 2021

Established relationships with relevant stakeholders in the scope of education and local cities of origin, as a distributor of information from and to external organizations, providing insight and increasing student interest in participating in external activities as well as held public events such as community service.

2019 - 2022